<?xml version="1.0"?><!--  <!DOCTYPE metadata SYSTEM "metadata.dtd">  --><metadata><idinfo><citation><citeinfo><origin>Minnesota Department of Education</origin><pubdate>20251119</pubdate><title>School Attendance Area Boundaries, Minnesota, SY2025-26</title><mgmg1cid></mgmg1cid><pubinfo><publish>Minnesota Department of Education</publish></pubinfo><ftname Sync="TRUE">sd_attendance11</ftname><geoform Sync="TRUE">vector digital data</geoform><onlink>https://gisdata.mn.gov/dataset/bdry-school-attendance-areas</onlink></citeinfo></citation><descript><abstract>This file represents the boundaries of all reported public school attendance areas in the state of Minnesota for school year 2025-26. Attendance areas attempt to represent the detailed sub-district breakdowns that determine where students attend elementary, middle, and high schools. These areas are unique to each public school system, and this file is only a generalization of those breakdowns.

In most cases, users are interested in the "dissolved" school district boundaries, without attendance area breakdowns. Those boundaries are available in a separate resource, with one record for each independent, common, and special school district in Minnesota. For many districts that operate only a few schools, attendance area breakdowns are not used or defined; in those cases, attendance areas are equivalent to district boundaries.

Each year Minnesota public school systems are asked to report any changes to their elementary, middle and high school attendance area boundaries. This file was developed from this annual information. Users should be aware that reporting compliance is not mandatory, so the information included is only as accurate as provided by those independent, common, and special school districts. Actual decisions on where students attend which schools are made entirely by the districts, and changes are not always reported to MDE.

Please also see Horizontal Positional Accuracy notes in the school district boundary dataset, many of which also apply to this layer.

</abstract><purpose>To keep this dataset current, the Minnesota Department of Education (MDE) asks school districts for any changes to district attendance boundaries on a yearly basis. This dataset, along with additional information from MDE databases, is used by MDE's Food and Nutrition Services Office to identify program financial priorities. It also is used in mapping products of school attendance area boundaries and school district boundaries; those products support a variety of mapping and data analysis applications.</purpose><supplinf>Minnesota</supplinf><langdata Sync="TRUE">en</langdata></descript><timeperd><current>Public school attendance boundaries updated for the school year identified in the Abstract</current><timeinfo><sngdate><caldate>20251119</caldate></sngdate></timeinfo></timeperd><status><progress>Complete</progress><update>Annually</update></status><spdom><lboundng><leftbc Sync="TRUE">189783.560000</leftbc><rightbc Sync="TRUE">761653.524100</rightbc><bottombc Sync="TRUE">4816309.330000</bottombc><topbc Sync="TRUE">5472346.500000</topbc></lboundng><bounding><westbc>-97.269688</westbc><eastbc>-89.397194</eastbc><northbc>49.403805</northbc><southbc>43.435423</southbc></bounding></spdom><keywords><theme><themekt>ISO 19115 Topic Category</themekt><themekey>boundaries, school, attendance boundary, attendance area, elementary school, middle school, high school, K-12</themekey></theme><place><placekey>Minnesota</placekey></place></keywords><accconst>None</accconst><useconst>If you obtain data from MDE, it is understood that you and/or your organization have the right to use it for any purpose.  If you modify it, you are encouraged to apply responsible best practices by documenting those changes in a metadata record.  If you transmit or provide the data to another user, it is your responsibility to provide appropriate content, limitation, warranty and liability information as you see fit.</useconst><browse><browsen>https://resources.gisdata.mn.gov/pub/gdrs/data/pub/us_mn_state_mde/bdry_school_attendance_areas/metadata/preview.jpg</browsen></browse><native>Microsoft Windows XP Version 5.1 (Build 2600) Service Pack 3; ESRI ArcCatalog 9.3.1.3500</native><natvform Sync="TRUE">Shapefile</natvform><crossref><citeinfo><title>bdry_school_district_boundaries, struc_school_program_locs</title></citeinfo></crossref><ptcontac><cntinfo><cntperp><cntorg>Minnesota Department of Education</cntorg><cntper>Data Specialists</cntper></cntperp><cntpos>Analytics Team</cntpos><cntaddr><addrtype>Mailling and Physical</addrtype><address>400 NE Stinson Blvd</address><city>Minneapolis</city><state>MN</state><postal>55413</postal></cntaddr><cntvoice>651-582-8200</cntvoice><cntemail>mde.analytics@state.mn.us</cntemail></cntinfo></ptcontac></idinfo><dataqual><attracc><attraccr>Each school district is asked to check the previous year's school district map for accuracy of school names and attendance boundaries. Reported changes are verified by MDE's GIS Coordinator. Not all school districts provide responses to the annual review.

Note 1: School names listed for elementary, middle, and high school attendance areas are often abbreviated for ease of labeling in maps.
Note 2: Not every school district operates the same way, and often multiple matriculation paths are available for students. These boundaries generally do not incorporate "magnet" schools or "regional" schools run by districts.
Note 3: In general, MDE staff attempt to associate schools serving grades KG-4 in the "elementary" (elem) columns, grades 5-8 in the "middle" (midd) columns, and grades 9-12 in the "high" columns. However, these are generalizations, and there are many situations where the grade splits between schools do not match exactly.
Note 4: The MDE team makes every effort to identify and demarcate "multiple" school situations. When the "&lt;levl&gt;_multi" columns designate a "multiple" situation with a "Y", the identifier shown in the "&lt;levl&gt;_orgid" column represents ONLY ONE of the schools named.
Note 5: Typically when the "&lt;levl&gt;_multi" columns designate a "multiple" situation with a "Y", a "choice" situations is represented in the "&lt;levl&gt;_name" column with an "OR" between the named schools, and a "combination" (such as splitting grades) is represented in the "&lt;levl&gt;_name" column with an "&amp;" between the named schools.</attraccr></attracc><logic>Data are topologically structured and verified.</logic><complete>Attendance areas for all school districts within Minnesota are included, but only as they are discovered by staff, or otherwise reported to MDE. Please note that airports are detached from school district boundaries as per MN 473.625., so coverage of the Minneapolis-St. Paul Airport is not included.</complete><posacc><horizpa><horizpar>Positional accuracy of the data sources varies widely. Source scales range between 1:24,000 and 1:100,000.  Many of the boundaries are hand-drawn by LEAs and provided to MDE on various media. Others are derived from PDF maps, provided shapefiles, or interactive attendance maps. See notes on potential boundary inaccuracies under 'Lineage', particularly for historical versions of this dataset.

To the extent possible, MDE uses county parcel data to determine overall district boundaries, which impact the attendance areas. Please read the accuracy notes on the school district boundary dataset if using this layer.

NOTES ON MISMATCHES OF DATA: because district boundaries are derived from this file, users should be aware of potential mismatches as identified in the metadata for school district boundaries.</horizpar></horizpa><vertacc><vertaccr>NA</vertaccr></vertacc></posacc><lineage><srcinfo><srcscale></srcscale></srcinfo><procstep><procdesc>For Lineage of this data prior to the current year, refer to metadata packaged with historical datasets available at the MN Geospatial Commons.

A small correction was made to this dataset on 2025-11-19 for the 2025-26 school year.</procdesc></procstep></lineage></dataqual><spdoinfo><direct>Vector</direct><mgmg3obj>Polygon</mgmg3obj><mgmg3til>State</mgmg3til><ptvctinf><esriterm Name="sd_attendance11"><efeatyp Sync="TRUE">Simple</efeatyp><efeageom Sync="TRUE">Polygon</efeageom><esritopo Sync="TRUE">FALSE</esritopo><efeacnt Sync="TRUE">826</efeacnt><spindex Sync="TRUE">FALSE</spindex><linrefer Sync="TRUE">FALSE</linrefer></esriterm><sdtsterm Name="sd_attendance11"><sdtstype Sync="TRUE">G-polygon</sdtstype><ptvctcnt Sync="TRUE">826</ptvctcnt></sdtsterm><esriterm Name="label"><efeatyp Sync="TRUE">Simple</efeatyp><efeageom Sync="TRUE">Label</efeageom><esritopo Sync="TRUE">FALSE</esritopo><efeacnt Sync="TRUE">1775</efeacnt><spindex Sync="TRUE">FALSE</spindex><linrefer Sync="TRUE">FALSE</linrefer></esriterm><sdtsterm Name="label"><sdtstype Sync="TRUE">Label point</sdtstype><ptvctcnt Sync="TRUE">1775</ptvctcnt></sdtsterm><esriterm Name="polygon"><efeatyp Sync="TRUE">Simple</efeatyp><efeageom Sync="TRUE">Polygon</efeageom><esritopo Sync="TRUE">TRUE</esritopo><efeacnt Sync="TRUE">1775</efeacnt><spindex Sync="TRUE">FALSE</spindex><linrefer Sync="TRUE">FALSE</linrefer></esriterm><sdtsterm Name="polygon"><sdtstype Sync="TRUE">GT-polygon composed of chains</sdtstype><ptvctcnt Sync="TRUE">1775</ptvctcnt></sdtsterm><esriterm Name="tic"><efeatyp Sync="TRUE">Simple</efeatyp><efeageom Sync="TRUE">Tic</efeageom><esritopo Sync="TRUE">FALSE</esritopo><efeacnt Sync="TRUE">4</efeacnt><spindex Sync="TRUE">FALSE</spindex><linrefer Sync="TRUE">FALSE</linrefer></esriterm><sdtsterm Name="tic"><sdtstype Sync="TRUE">Point</sdtstype><ptvctcnt Sync="TRUE">4</ptvctcnt></sdtsterm></ptvctinf><indspref></indspref></spdoinfo><spref><vertdef><altsys><altdatum>not applicable</altdatum><altunits>not applicable</altunits></altsys><depthsys><depthdn>not applicable</depthdn><depthdu>not applicable</depthdu></depthsys></vertdef><horizsys><planar><gridsys><gridsysn>Universal Transverse Mercator</gridsysn><utm><utmzone>15</utmzone></utm></gridsys><planci><plandu>meters</plandu></planci></planar><geodetic><horizdn>NAD83</horizdn><ellips>GRS80</ellips></geodetic></horizsys></spref><eainfo><overview><eaover>Field listing, by sample record:
sdorgid: 10011000000
sdtype:	01
sdnumber: 0011
sdprefname: Anoka-Hennepin Public School District
elem_orgid: 10011420000
elem_name: Wilson
elem_multi: N
midd_orgid: 10011034000
midd_name: Arts Moore &amp; Washington
midd_multi: Y
high_orgid: 10011001000
high_name: Anoka
high_multi: N

Details on individual columns:
sdorgid: unique ORG ID number used to link the district to the "MDE ORG" database. See Detailed Citation for a link where that database can be searched.

sdtype:  In state statute, there are three types of school districts that have boundaries. This type identifier, used at MDE, describes the types as follows:
   03 - "Special" School Districts: includes only Minneapolis (SD #0001) and South St. Paul (SD #0006)
   02 - Common School Districts: includes only Franconia (SD #0323) and Prinsburg (SD #0815)
   01 - Independent School Districts
(Note also that Minneapolis and Aitkin school districts both have a school district identifier (sdnumber) of "1" or "0001", making this identifier important for uniqueness.)

sdnumber: School district number (i.e. 2908 for Brandon-Evansville, 0001 for Aitkin and Minneapolis, 0011 for Anoka-Hennepin, etc)

sdprefname: School district name, derived from the organization's "preferred name" within the MDE ORG database. (Prior publications used a more simplified name.)

elem_orgid: the 11-digit ORG ID number used to uniquely identify the elementary school named in the "elem_name" column.

elem_name: Elementary school name of the primary elementary school within the attendance area. Multiple names may be listed for various reasons described below.

elem_multi: A designator intended to convey when students within an area can choose to attend multiple elementary schools or other various scenarios, such as PK-KG centers or elementary buildings that split grades.

midd_orgid: the 11-digit ORG ID number used to uniquely identify the middle school named in the "midd_name" column

midd_name: Middle school name of the primary middle school within the attendance area. In many cases, this is blank because some districts only have elementary and secondary schools.

midd_multi: A designator intended to convey when students within an area can choose to attend multiple middle schools, or other various scenarios, such as separate middle school and junior high buildings.

high_orgid: the 11-digit ORG ID number used to uniquely identify the high school named in the "high_name" column

high_name: High school name of the primary high school within the attendance area.

high_multi: A designator intended to convey when students within an area can choose to attend multiple high schools or other various scenarios, such as split secondary buildings.
</eaover><eadetcit>More current information on school districts can be obtained from MDE ORG at https://pub.education.mn.gov/MdeOrgView/</eadetcit></overview></eainfo><distinfo><resdesc>bdry_school_attendance_areas</resdesc><distliab>The Geographic Information System (GIS) Data to which this notice is attached are made available pursuant to the Minnesota Government Data Practices Act (Minnesota Statutes Chapter 13). The Minnesota Department of Education (MDE) does not warrant the results you may obtain by using this dataset. This dataset is provided ''as is'' without express or implied warranties, including warranties of merchantability and fitness. In no event will MDE be liable for any consequential, incidental or special damages, including any lost profits or lost savings, even if an MDE representative has been advised of the possibility of such damages or any other claim by any third party.

In obtaining this data from MDE and MnGeo, it is understood that you and/or your organization have the right to use it for any purpose.  If you modify it, you are encouraged to apply responsible best practices by documenting those changes in a metadata record.  If you transmit or provide the data to another user, it is your responsibility to provide appropriate content, limitation, warranty and liability information as you see fit.

MnGeo's data disclaimer is online: https://www.mngeo.state.mn.us/chouse/disclaimer.html</distliab><stdorder><digform><digtinfo><formname>Shapefile</formname><transize>5 megabytes, zipped</transize><dssize Sync="TRUE">3.567</dssize><formvern></formvern></digtinfo></digform><ordering>The GIS data and maps are distributed on the internet by clicking below after Online Linkage.</ordering></stdorder><distrib><cntinfo><cntperp><cntorg>Minnesota Department of Education</cntorg><cntper>Data Specialists</cntper></cntperp><cntpos>Analytics Team</cntpos><cntaddr><addrtype>mailing and physical</addrtype><address>400 NE Stinson Blvd</address><city>Minneapolis</city><state>MN</state><postal>55413</postal></cntaddr><cntvoice>651-582-8200</cntvoice><cntemail>mde.analytics@state.mn.us</cntemail></cntinfo></distrib></distinfo><metainfo><metd>20251119</metd><metstdn>Minnesota Geographic Metadata Guidelines</metstdn><metstdv>1.2</metstdv><metextns><onlink>https://www.mngeo.state.mn.us/committee/standards/mgmg/metadata.htm</onlink></metextns><langmeta Sync="TRUE">en</langmeta><mettc Sync="TRUE">local time</mettc><metextns><onlink Sync="TRUE">http://www.esri.com/metadata/esriprof80.html</onlink><metprof Sync="TRUE">ESRI Metadata Profile</metprof></metextns><metc><cntinfo><cntperp><cntorg>Minnesota Department of Education</cntorg><cntper>Data Specialists</cntper></cntperp><cntpos>Analytics Team</cntpos><cntaddr><addrtype>mailing and physical</addrtype><address>400 NE Stinson Blvd</address><city>Minneapolis</city><state>MN</state><postal>55413</postal></cntaddr><cntvoice>651-582-8200</cntvoice><cntemail>mde.analytics@state.mn.us</cntemail></cntinfo></metc></metainfo><Esri><CreaDate>20151019</CreaDate><CreaTime>09421100</CreaTime><SyncOnce>FALSE</SyncOnce><SyncDate>20100913</SyncDate><SyncTime>15163100</SyncTime><ModDate>20110923</ModDate><ModTime>11001200</ModTime><DataProperties><itemProps><itemLocation><linkage Sync="TRUE">file://\\edu-gisprod10b\e$\Project_Information\Metadata\Education\sd_attend1516</linkage><protocol Sync="TRUE">Local Area Network</protocol></itemLocation></itemProps><copyHistory><copy source="A:\Spatial_Data\Education\sd_attend1516" dest="\\edu-gisprod10b\e$\Project_Information\Metadata\Education\sd_attend1516" date="20151019" time="09424900"></copy></copyHistory></DataProperties></Esri><dataIdInfo><envirDesc Sync="TRUE">Microsoft Windows XP Version 5.1 (Build 2600) Service Pack 3; ESRI ArcCatalog 9.3.1.3500</envirDesc><dataLang><languageCode Sync="TRUE" value="en"></languageCode></dataLang><idCitation><resTitle Sync="TRUE">sd_attendance11</resTitle><presForm><PresFormCd Sync="TRUE" value="005"></PresFormCd></presForm></idCitation><spatRpType><SpatRepTypCd Sync="TRUE" value="001"></SpatRepTypCd></spatRpType><dataExt><geoEle><GeoBndBox esriExtentType="native"><westBL Sync="TRUE">189783.56</westBL><eastBL Sync="TRUE">761653.5241</eastBL><northBL Sync="TRUE">5472346.5</northBL><southBL Sync="TRUE">4816309.33</southBL><exTypeCode Sync="TRUE">1</exTypeCode></GeoBndBox></geoEle></dataExt><geoBox esriExtentType="decdegrees"><westBL Sync="TRUE">-97.269688</westBL><eastBL Sync="TRUE">-89.397194</eastBL><northBL Sync="TRUE">49.403805</northBL><southBL Sync="TRUE">43.435423</southBL><exTypeCode Sync="TRUE">1</exTypeCode></geoBox></dataIdInfo><mdLang><languageCode Sync="TRUE" value="en"></languageCode></mdLang><mdStanName Sync="TRUE">ISO 19115 Geographic Information - Metadata</mdStanName><mdStanVer Sync="TRUE">DIS_ESRI1.0</mdStanVer><mdChar><CharSetCd Sync="TRUE" value="004"></CharSetCd></mdChar><mdHrLv><ScopeCd Sync="TRUE" value="005"></ScopeCd></mdHrLv><mdHrLvName Sync="TRUE">dataset</mdHrLvName><distInfo><distributor><distorTran><onLineSrc><orDesc Sync="TRUE">002</orDesc><linkage Sync="TRUE">file://\\8HP25J1\E$\MDEFNS_Data\Spatial_Data\SD_Data\SY2010-11\Final_Datasets\MNGEO\sd_attendance11.shp</linkage><protocol Sync="TRUE">Local Area Network</protocol></onLineSrc><transSize Sync="TRUE">3.567</transSize></distorTran><distorFormat><formatName Sync="TRUE">Shapefile</formatName></distorFormat></distributor></distInfo><refSysInfo><RefSystem><refSysID><identCode Sync="TRUE">NAD_1983_UTM_Zone_15N</identCode></refSysID></RefSystem></refSysInfo><spatRepInfo><VectSpatRep><topLvl><TopoLevCd Sync="TRUE" value="001"></TopoLevCd></topLvl><geometObjs Name="sd_attendance11"><geoObjTyp><GeoObjTypCd Sync="TRUE" value="001"></GeoObjTypCd></geoObjTyp><geoObjCnt Sync="TRUE">826</geoObjCnt></geometObjs></VectSpatRep></spatRepInfo><mdDateSt Sync="TRUE">20110923</mdDateSt></metadata>