<?xml version="1.0"?><!--  <!DOCTYPE metadata SYSTEM "metadata.dtd">  --><metadata><idinfo><citation><citeinfo><origin>Minnesota Department of Education</origin><pubdate>20251008</pubdate><title>School District Boundaries, Minnesota, SY2025-26</title><mgmg1cid></mgmg1cid><pubinfo><publish>Minnesota Department of Education</publish></pubinfo><ftname Sync="TRUE">sd2011</ftname><geoform Sync="TRUE">vector digital data</geoform><onlink>https://gisdata.mn.gov/dataset/bdry-school-district-boundaries</onlink></citeinfo></citation><descript><abstract>This file represents a statewide compilation of the boundaries of all independent, common, and special school districts in the state of Minnesota. Minnesota school districts are asked to report any changes to their district boundaries annually. With the exception of consolidations, dissolutions, or other financial cooperation agreements, the reporting is not mandatory. As independent special purpose government organizations, school districts determine their own district &amp; attendance boundaries, working with neighboring districts and county auditors to ensure proper taxation. The Minnesota Department of Education (MDE) plays no role in determining the actual boundaries.

Since 2008, district boundaries have also been reviewed against the school district coding provided in county parcels, where it exists. (Parcel data are supplied by counties to MnGeo, who in turn share that with MDE.) The results are overall increased accuracy, but also increased complexity. Conversations with county GIS coordinators and auditors are ongoing with respect to the complex situations reflected within county parcel data, and whether or not these are accurate representations of school district boundaries. Since school year 2021, many "islands" or other unusual situations have been eliminated or simplified as a result of those conversations.

This file is not intended to represent the "true" boundaries with respect to taxation, but as generalized boundaries focused on ensuring accurate representation in residential areas. As a result, starting in 2021, boundaries have been simplified by removing complex situations in non-residential areas, such as transportation Right-of-Way (ROW), publicly-owned land, tax exempt land, or water. This simplification work is expected to continue each year.

This data is now also available in CSV format. OBJECTID and Shape columns have been removed from that format.</abstract><purpose>This school district boundary information is developed as a GIS dataset and, along with additional information, is used by the Minnesota Department of Education for various regulatory and advisory purposes, including identifying program financial priorities and reporting to the US Census Bureau.

As independent special purpose government organizations, school districts determine their own district and attendance boundaries, working with neighboring districts and county auditors to ensure proper taxation. The Minnesota Department of Education (MDE) plays no role in determining the actual boundaries. MNIT staff supporting MDE merely attempt to compile the most accurate representation possible, particularly focused on boundaries that affect housing.</purpose><supplinf>Minnesota</supplinf><langdata Sync="TRUE">en</langdata></descript><timeperd><current>Public school district boundaries, dissolved from school attendance area boundaries, for the school year idenfitied in the title.</current><timeinfo><sngdate><caldate>20251008</caldate></sngdate></timeinfo></timeperd><status><progress>Complete</progress><update>Annually</update></status><spdom><lboundng><leftbc Sync="TRUE">189783.560000</leftbc><rightbc Sync="TRUE">761653.524100</rightbc><bottombc Sync="TRUE">4816309.330000</bottombc><topbc Sync="TRUE">5472346.500000</topbc></lboundng><bounding><westbc>-97.269688</westbc><eastbc>-89.397194</eastbc><northbc>49.403805</northbc><southbc>43.435423</southbc></bounding></spdom><keywords><theme><themekey>boundaries, school, districts, school districts, district boundaries, schools, public, independent</themekey><themekt>ISO 19115 Topic Category</themekt></theme><place><placekey>Minnesota</placekey></place></keywords><accconst>None</accconst><useconst>If you obtain data from MDE or MnGeo, it is understood that you and/or your organization have the right to use them for any purpose. If you modify them, you are encouraged to apply responsible best practices by documenting those changes in a metadata record.  If you transmit or provide the data to another user, it is your responsibility to provide appropriate content, limitation, warranty and liability information as you see fit.</useconst><browse><browsen>https://resources.gisdata.mn.gov/pub/gdrs/data/pub/us_mn_state_mde/bdry_school_district_boundaries/metadata/preview.jpg</browsen></browse><native>Microsoft Windows XP Version 5.1 (Build 2600) Service Pack 3; ESRI ArcCatalog 9.3.1.3500</native><natvform Sync="TRUE">Shapefile</natvform><crossref><citeinfo><title>bdry_school_attendance areas, struc_school_program_locs</title></citeinfo></crossref><ptcontac><cntinfo><cntperp><cntorg>Minnesota Department of Education</cntorg><cntper>Data Specialists</cntper></cntperp><cntpos>Analytics Team</cntpos><cntaddr><addrtype>Mailling and Physical</addrtype><address>400 NE Stinson Blvd</address><city>Minneapolis</city><state>MN</state><postal>55413</postal></cntaddr><cntvoice>651-582-8200</cntvoice><cntemail>mde.analytics@state.mn.us</cntemail></cntinfo></ptcontac></idinfo><dataqual><attracc><attraccr>Each school district checks the previous year's map for accuracy of school names and boundaries. Changes are verified by the Minnesota Department of Education. School district boundaries are dissolved from a larger statewide school district file containing elementary, middle and high school attendance boundaries. Boundaries are maintained within a relational database.</attraccr></attracc><logic>Data are topologically structured and verified.</logic><complete>All independent, common, and special school districts within Minnesota are included. Prior publications included a boundary for the Minneapolis-St. Paul International Airport; this record was removed for increased compatibility with the MDE ORG database. It is no longer included in the Richfield Area school district boundary, but is instead represented as a "hole" in the dataset. (Please note that airports are “detached” from school district boundaries as per MN 473.625.)</complete><posacc><horizpa><horizpar>Positional accuracy of the data sources varies widely. Source scales range between 1:24,000 (or less) and 1:100,000. In early compilations, many of the boundaries were hand-drawn by the school districts.

In an ongoing process since 2008, school district boundaries have been modified to a greater accuracy using county parcel datasets. In general, non-residential areas are reviewed at a scale of 1:24,000, and residential areas at a scale of 1:10,000. See notes on simplification efforts in the Abstract, and on potential boundary inaccuracies under 'Lineage', particularly within metadata on historical versions of this dataset.

In situations where gaps or overlaps of county parcel data exist, assuming housing isn't impacted, Census geographic boundaries are used as the "tie breaker". These are frequently seen along major riverways that also serve as county boundaries. As a result of this alignment, there may be some small areas, without housing, where the county taxation of the property is slightly different than what is reflected in these boundaries.
</horizpar></horizpa></posacc><lineage><srcinfo></srcinfo><procstep><procdesc>For a detailed lineage of the development of this dataset, refer to the metadata packaged with the historical versions available on the MN Geospatial Commons.

For school year 2025-26, no major consolidations or dissolutions were executed. Only minor boundary changes were implemented, when discovered via review of county parcel/taxation data or county auditor notifications. 

NOTES ON MISMATCHES OF DATA:

1. The County Auditor's Office is required to delineate school district boundaries by law, and maintains the official record for tax purposes. Note that school districts also have boundary maps, and that, while the two sets of map boundaries should match, they do not always. In cases where the school district and the county auditor records show different boundaries, this should be resolved locally first before suggesting updates to MDE. Statewide compilation efforts are complicated when updates are obtained from multiple sources.

2. Mismatches between the Census Boundary lines and the School District lines: although the school district boundary file generally uses Census geography where possible, it does not always follow precisely. Therefore, mismatches between this file and school district boundaries maintained by the Census can be legitimate. As of 2019, MDE is updating Census versions via the Census School District Reporting Program (SDRP) annually. However, due to the limitations of this program, there will always be mismatches, particularly along detailed borders such as those defined by water bodies.
</procdesc><proccont><cntinfo><cntperp><cntper>Mike Dolbow</cntper><cntorg>MNIT Partnering with Education</cntorg></cntperp><cntpos>GIS Coordinator</cntpos><cntaddr><addrtype>mailing address</addrtype><address>400 NE Stinson Blvd</address><city>Minneapolis</city><state>MN</state><postal>55413</postal><country>USA</country></cntaddr><cntvoice>651-582-8789</cntvoice><cntemail>mike.dolbow@state.mn.us</cntemail><hours>0700 - 1530</hours></cntinfo></proccont><procsv>ArcMAP 9.1</procsv><procdate>May 2008</procdate><proctime>3 months</proctime></procstep></lineage></dataqual><spdoinfo><direct>Vector</direct><mgmg3obj>Polygon</mgmg3obj><mgmg3til>State</mgmg3til><ptvctinf><esriterm Name="sd2011"><efeatyp Sync="TRUE">Simple</efeatyp><efeageom Sync="TRUE">Polygon</efeageom><esritopo Sync="TRUE">FALSE</esritopo><efeacnt Sync="TRUE">338</efeacnt><spindex Sync="TRUE">TRUE</spindex><linrefer Sync="TRUE">FALSE</linrefer></esriterm><sdtsterm Name="sd2011"><sdtstype Sync="TRUE">G-polygon</sdtstype><ptvctcnt Sync="TRUE">338</ptvctcnt></sdtsterm></ptvctinf></spdoinfo><spref><vertdef><altsys><altdatum>not applicable</altdatum></altsys><depthsys><depthdn>not applicable</depthdn></depthsys></vertdef><horizsys><planar><gridsys><gridsysn>Universal Transverse Mercator</gridsysn><utm><utmzone>15</utmzone></utm></gridsys><planci><plandu>meters</plandu></planci></planar><geodetic><horizdn>NAD83</horizdn><ellips>GRS80</ellips></geodetic></horizsys></spref><eainfo><overview><eaover>Column description, using a sample record:
sdorgid: 10728000000
formid: 0728-01 
sdtype: 01
sdnumber: 0728
prefname: Elk River Public School District
shortname: Elk River
web_url: http://www.isd728.org
sqmiles: 169.5076
acres: 108485.3698
Detailed overview of columns:
sdorgid: unique numeric identifier used to link with the MDE ORG database.

formid: This is a concatenated character field of sdnumber, a dash, and sdtype. This can be used for lookup in the MDE ORG reporting application.

sdtype: This is an MDE two-character identifier describing the type of school district:
  "01" - Independent Districts and Schools
  "02" - includes only two Common Districts: Franconia-0323, Prinsburg-0815
  "03" - includes only two Special Districts: Minneapolis-0001, South St. Paul-0006

sdnumber: Four-character school district number, left-padded with zeroes. i.e. 2908 (Brandon-Evansville) or 0110 (Waconia).

prefname: "preferred name" of the School District from the MDE ORG database. Note inconsistent spelling, formats, and abbreviations of "District" exist due to the preferences of each individual district.

shortname: Shortened/simplified name of the district, useful for map labeling and consistency.

web_url: School district website, where available, from the MDE ORG database.

sqmiles: Square miles for each district, derived from the shape of the polygon.

acres: Acres for each district, derived from the shape of the polygon.
</eaover><eadetcit>More current information on school districts can be obtained from MDE ORG at https://pub.education.mn.gov/MdeOrgView/</eadetcit></overview></eainfo><distinfo><resdesc>bdry_school_district_boundaries</resdesc><distliab>The Minnesota Department of Education (MDE) does not warrant the results you may obtain by using this dataset. This dataset is provided ''as is'' without express or implied warranties, including warranties of merchantability and fitness. In no event will MDE be liable for any consequential, incidental or special damages, including any lost profits or lost savings, even if an MDE  representative has been advised of the possibility of such damages or any other claim by any third party.

In obtaining this data from MDE and MnGeo, it is understood that you and/or your organization have the right to use them for any purpose. If you modify them, you are encouraged to apply responsible best practices by documenting those changes in a metadata record.  If you transmit or provide the data to another user, it is your responsibility to provide appropriate content, limitation, warranty and liability information as you see fit.

MnGeo's disclaimer is online:  https://www.mngeo.state.mn.us/chouse/disclaimer.html</distliab><stdorder><digform><digtinfo><formname>Shapefile</formname><transize>less than 1 megabyte</transize><dssize Sync="TRUE">3.030</dssize></digtinfo></digform><ordering>The GIS data and maps are distributed on the internet by clicking below after Online Linkage.</ordering></stdorder><distrib><cntinfo><cntperp><cntorg>Minnesota Department of Education</cntorg><cntper>Data Specialists</cntper></cntperp><cntpos>Analytics Team</cntpos><cntaddr><addrtype>mailing and physical</addrtype><address>400 NE Stinson Blvd</address><city>Minneapolis</city><state>MN</state><postal>55413</postal></cntaddr><cntvoice>651-582-8200</cntvoice><cntemail>mde.analytics@state.mn.us</cntemail></cntinfo></distrib></distinfo><metainfo><metd>20251008</metd><metstdn>Minnesota Geographic Metadata Guidelines</metstdn><metstdv>1.2</metstdv><metextns><onlink>https://www.mngeo.state.mn.us/committee/standards/mgmg/metadata.htm</onlink></metextns><langmeta Sync="TRUE">en</langmeta><mettc Sync="TRUE">local time</mettc><metextns><onlink Sync="TRUE">http://www.esri.com/metadata/esriprof80.html</onlink><metprof Sync="TRUE">ESRI Metadata Profile</metprof></metextns><metc><cntinfo><cntperp><cntorg>Minnesota Department of Education</cntorg><cntper>Data Specialists</cntper></cntperp><cntpos>Analytics Team</cntpos><cntaddr><addrtype>mailing and physical</addrtype><address>400 NE Stinson Blvd</address><city>Minneapolis</city><state>MN</state><postal>55413</postal></cntaddr><cntvoice>651-582-8200</cntvoice><cntemail>mde.analytics@state.mn.us</cntemail></cntinfo></metc></metainfo><Esri><ModDate>20110923</ModDate><ModTime>10545100</ModTime><CreaDate>20151019</CreaDate><CreaTime>09421100</CreaTime><SyncOnce>FALSE</SyncOnce><SyncDate>20100913</SyncDate><SyncTime>15162900</SyncTime><DataProperties><itemProps><itemLocation><linkage Sync="TRUE">file://\\edu-gisprod10b\e$\Project_Information\Metadata\Education\sd_1516</linkage><protocol Sync="TRUE">Local Area Network</protocol></itemLocation></itemProps><copyHistory><copy source="A:\Spatial_Data\Education\sd_1516" dest="\\edu-gisprod10b\e$\Project_Information\Metadata\Education\sd_1516" date="20151019" time="09424500"></copy></copyHistory></DataProperties></Esri><mdDateSt Sync="TRUE">20110923</mdDateSt><dataIdInfo><envirDesc Sync="TRUE">Microsoft Windows XP Version 5.1 (Build 2600) Service Pack 3; ESRI ArcCatalog 9.3.1.3500</envirDesc><dataLang><languageCode Sync="TRUE" value="en"></languageCode></dataLang><idCitation><resTitle Sync="TRUE">sd2011</resTitle><presForm><PresFormCd Sync="TRUE" value="005"></PresFormCd></presForm></idCitation><spatRpType><SpatRepTypCd Sync="TRUE" value="001"></SpatRepTypCd></spatRpType><dataExt><geoEle><GeoBndBox esriExtentType="native"><westBL Sync="TRUE">189783.56</westBL><eastBL Sync="TRUE">761653.5241</eastBL><northBL Sync="TRUE">5472346.5</northBL><southBL Sync="TRUE">4816309.33</southBL><exTypeCode Sync="TRUE">1</exTypeCode></GeoBndBox></geoEle></dataExt><geoBox esriExtentType="decdegrees"><westBL Sync="TRUE">-97.269688</westBL><eastBL Sync="TRUE">-89.397194</eastBL><northBL Sync="TRUE">49.403805</northBL><southBL Sync="TRUE">43.435423</southBL><exTypeCode Sync="TRUE">1</exTypeCode></geoBox></dataIdInfo><mdLang><languageCode Sync="TRUE" value="en"></languageCode></mdLang><mdStanName Sync="TRUE">ISO 19115 Geographic Information - Metadata</mdStanName><mdStanVer Sync="TRUE">DIS_ESRI1.0</mdStanVer><mdChar><CharSetCd Sync="TRUE" value="004"></CharSetCd></mdChar><mdHrLv><ScopeCd Sync="TRUE" value="005"></ScopeCd></mdHrLv><mdHrLvName Sync="TRUE">dataset</mdHrLvName><distInfo><distributor><distorTran><onLineSrc><orDesc Sync="TRUE">002</orDesc><linkage Sync="TRUE">file://\\8HP25J1\E$\MDEFNS_Data\Spatial_Data\SD_Data\SY2010-11\Final_Datasets\MNGEO\sd2011.shp</linkage><protocol Sync="TRUE">Local Area Network</protocol></onLineSrc><transSize Sync="TRUE">3.030</transSize></distorTran><distorFormat><formatName Sync="TRUE">Shapefile</formatName></distorFormat></distributor></distInfo><spatRepInfo><VectSpatRep><topLvl><TopoLevCd Sync="TRUE" value="001"></TopoLevCd></topLvl><geometObjs Name="sd2011"><geoObjTyp><GeoObjTypCd Sync="TRUE" value="001"></GeoObjTypCd></geoObjTyp><geoObjCnt Sync="TRUE">338</geoObjCnt></geometObjs></VectSpatRep></spatRepInfo><refSysInfo><RefSystem><refSysID><identCode Sync="TRUE">NAD_1983_UTM_Zone_15N</identCode></refSysID></RefSystem></refSysInfo></metadata>