<?xml version="1.0"?><!--  <!DOCTYPE metadata SYSTEM "metadata.dtd">  --><metadata><idinfo><citation><citeinfo><origin>Minnesota Department of Education</origin><pubdate>20251031</pubdate><title>Public School Buildings in Minnesota</title><mgmg1cid></mgmg1cid><pubinfo><publish>Minnesota Department of Education</publish></pubinfo><ftname Sync="TRUE">nonpub07</ftname><geoform Sync="TRUE">vector digital data</geoform><onlink>https://gisdata.mn.gov/dataset/struc-school-buildings</onlink></citeinfo></citation><descript><supplinf>Minnesota</supplinf><langdata Sync="TRUE">en</langdata><abstract>This data set represents footprints of buildings that primarily serve as sites for delivering non-charter, K-12 public education in Minnesota. The goal is to discretely and uniquely identify specific buildings, designated by specific street addresses, that house one or more active public school programs. More specifically, school programs classified as elementary, middle, junior high, senior high, or secondary, delivered by independent or special school districts.

In contrast to MDE's annually updated school program locations data set that uniquely identifies specific programs, when a single building houses multiple programs, this data set will have just one record. For example, a single building might house a district office, an ECFE program, an elementary program, and a middle school program. In this case, the name assigned will be for the "highest classification" - in other words, the middle school program. This is often an oversimplified name for the building, but it is more complete than relying on incomplete building names from OpenStreetMap (OSM).

This data set is designed for geospatial software users who require basic details (building name and address) on locations of buildings that are primarily used for public education, but also are frequently used for other community needs. It covers most, but not all, active public school program locations (see Completeness section). It does not include charter schools, private schools, or buildings delivering educational programs outside of grades K-12, such as early childhood centers delivering only pre-K programs. (Early childhood centers including at least a KG grade are included.)</abstract><purpose>The intended purpose of this dataset is to identify "major" buildings where public K-12 school programs are actively being delivered. These buildings frequently have unique qualities and play a unique role within local communities, and this data set can serve as a "simpler" view of public education facilities than MDE's school program locations dataset. It should NOT be used to identify every place where educational programs are taking place, because there are several exceptions to the buildings included (see the Abstract and Completeness sections). If you need to identify any place educational programs are delivered, use the struc-school-program-locs dataset.</purpose></descript><status><progress>Complete</progress><update>As needed</update></status><spdom><lboundng><leftbc Sync="TRUE">199551.594331</leftbc><rightbc Sync="TRUE">636157.436282</rightbc><bottombc Sync="TRUE">4820393.001650</bottombc><topbc Sync="TRUE">5385889.998627</topbc></lboundng><bounding><westbc>-97.071908</westbc><eastbc>-91.152757</eastbc><northbc>48.626078</northbc><southbc>43.476096</southbc></bounding></spdom><keywords><theme><themekey>structure, school, schools, public school, building, buildings</themekey><themekt>ISO 19115 Topic Category</themekt></theme><place><placekey>Minnesota</placekey></place></keywords><accconst>None</accconst><useconst>In obtaining this data from MDE and MnGeo, it is understood that you and/or your organization have the right to use it for any purpose. If you modify it, you are encouraged to apply responsible best practices by documenting those changes in a metadata record. If you transmit or provide the data to another user, it is your responsibility to provide appropriate content, limitation, warranty and liability information as you see fit.</useconst><native>Microsoft Windows XP Version 5.1 (Build 2600) Service Pack 2; ESRI ArcCatalog 9.1.0.780</native><crossref><citeinfo><title>Current School program locations: https://gisdata.mn.gov/dataset/struc-school-program-locs</title></citeinfo></crossref><natvform Sync="TRUE">Shapefile</natvform><timeperd><timeinfo><sngdate><caldate>20251031</caldate></sngdate></timeinfo><current>This dataset is current as of the date shown, and will be updated as needed, typically annually.</current></timeperd><ptcontac><cntinfo><cntperp><cntorg>Minnesota Department of Education</cntorg><cntper>Data Specialists</cntper></cntperp><cntpos>Analytics Team</cntpos><cntaddr><addrtype>Mailling and Physical</addrtype><address>400 NE Stinson Blvd</address><city>Minneapolis</city><state>MN</state><postal>55413</postal></cntaddr><cntvoice>651-582-8200</cntvoice><cntemail>mde.analytics@state.mn.us</cntemail></cntinfo></ptcontac></idinfo><dataqual><attracc><attraccr>Spot checks have been performed on this dataset, but no guarantee of accuracy is provided. While MNIT staff track OSM edits to school buildings daily, and learn about new construction via MDE-ORG, they have few mechanisms to track reconstruction projects that may significantly alter existing K12 building footprints.</attraccr></attracc><logic>Not applicable</logic><lineage><srcinfo><srcscale></srcscale></srcinfo><procstep><proccont><cntinfo><cntperp><cntper>Mike Dolbow</cntper><cntorg>MNIT Partnering with Education</cntorg></cntperp><cntpos>GIS Coordinator</cntpos><cntaddr><addrtype>mailing address</addrtype><address>400 NE Stinson Blvd</address><city>Minneapolis</city><state>MN</state><postal>55413</postal><country>USA</country></cntaddr><cntvoice>651-582-8789</cntvoice><cntemail>mike.dolbow@state.mn.us</cntemail><hours>0700 - 1530</hours></cntinfo></proccont><procsv>ArcMAP 9.1</procsv><procdate>May 2006</procdate><procdesc>Building footprints are sourced from OpenStreetMap (https://www.openstreetmap.org), downloaded via the "Quick OSM" QGIS plugin, which leverages the Overpass API. The simple query performed is for buildings tagged as "school" or "kindergarten" within the boundary of Minnesota.

More information on the quick OSM plugin is available at https://plugins.qgis.org/plugins/QuickOSM/

Footprints are then merged with MDE organizational information on active public schools for building name and address information. When more than one program is housed in a building, the "highest classification" in terms of grade levels is used for the building name. For example, if a building houses both a middle school and a high school, the name of the high school is used for the building. When more than one building is present at a specific site, but only one street address is used, only the building intersecting the main school locations is used.</procdesc></procstep></lineage><complete>This dataset consists of almost 1200 buildings, covering all active public, non-charter, K-12 programs in MDE's organization database other than the exceptions listed below. Please note that building footprints sourced from OpenStreetMap (OSM) may be outdated; for example, if a building expands or contracts, but the older footprint still contains the K12 school point, the new footprint might not be reflected in this dataset.

Please also note that two types of buildings tagged as school buildings in OSM are withheld from this dataset:
1) Buildings that no longer house active K-12 school programs, such as Central Elementary in Bemidji. There are many former school buildings that are still standing, but as of the publication date were not housing active public school programs.
2) Buildings that do not intersect the "main" site for delivering school programs. These can be "outbuildings" or merely separate polygons created in OSM for specific details. (Often a single building is broken up into separate polygons.) They can also exist in specific situations where districts have multiple buildings on a site but have consolidated programs into one record with a single address.

Additional exceptions to active public school K-12 programs that are not included in this dataset are identified by state organization ID and brief descriptions below:
--Buildings that are more than just "schools", so didn't make sense to tag as a school building in Open Street Map:
10707001000 -- Nett Lake Elementary
30001363000 --Wellstone International High in Minneapolis
--Religious Colony schools:
12888006000, 12888007000 -- Lismore Colony Schools
12689006000 -- Heartland Colony
10150011000 -- Spring Prairie Colony
12888004000,12888010000 -- Big Stone Colony schools
--Other situations:
10882062000 --Monticello Nature-based Education

In fall 2025, some early childhood centers that did not house kindergarten programs were removed.</complete><posacc><horizpa><horizpar>Unknown</horizpar></horizpa><vertacc><vertaccr>NA</vertaccr></vertacc></posacc></dataqual><spdoinfo><direct>Point</direct><mgmg3obj>Point</mgmg3obj><mgmg3til>State</mgmg3til><ptvctinf><esriterm Name="nonpub07"><efeatyp Sync="TRUE">Simple</efeatyp><efeageom Sync="TRUE">Point</efeageom><esritopo Sync="TRUE">FALSE</esritopo><efeacnt Sync="TRUE">602</efeacnt><spindex Sync="TRUE">TRUE</spindex><linrefer Sync="TRUE">FALSE</linrefer></esriterm><sdtsterm Name="nonpub07"><sdtstype Sync="TRUE">Entity point</sdtstype><ptvctcnt Sync="TRUE">602</ptvctcnt></sdtsterm></ptvctinf><indspref></indspref></spdoinfo><spref><vertdef><altsys><altdatum>not applicable</altdatum></altsys><depthsys><depthdn>not applicable</depthdn></depthsys></vertdef><horizsys><planar><gridsys><gridsysn>Universal Transverse Mercator</gridsysn><utm><utmzone>15</utmzone></utm></gridsys><planci><plandu>meters</plandu></planci></planar><geodetic><horizdn>NAD83</horizdn><ellips>GRS80</ellips></geodetic></horizsys></spref><distinfo><resdesc>uvw_struc_school_buildings_mn</resdesc><distliab>The Minnesota Department of Education (MDE) does not warrant the results you may obtain by using this dataset. This dataset is provided ''as is'' without express or implied warranties, including warranties of merchantability and fitness. In no event will MDE be liable for any consequential, incidental or special damages, including any lost profits or lost savings, even if an MDE representative has been advised of the possibility of such damages or any other claim by any third party.

In obtaining this data from MDE and MnGeo, it is understood that you and/or your organization have the right to use it for any purpose. If you modify it, you are encouraged to apply responsible best practices by documenting those changes in a metadata record. If you transmit or provide the data to another user, it is your responsibility to provide appropriate content, limitation, warranty and liability information as you see fit. </distliab><stdorder><digform><digtinfo><formname>Shapefile</formname><transize>less than 1 megabyte</transize><dssize Sync="TRUE">0.016</dssize><formvern></formvern></digtinfo></digform><ordering>The GIS data and maps are distributed on the internet by clicking below after Online Linkage.</ordering></stdorder><distrib><cntinfo><cntperp><cntorg>Minnesota Department of Education</cntorg><cntper>Data Specialists</cntper></cntperp><cntpos>Analytics Team</cntpos><cntaddr><addrtype>mailing and physical</addrtype><address>400 NE Stinson Blvd</address><city>Minneapolis</city><state>MN</state><postal>55413</postal></cntaddr><cntvoice>651-582-8200</cntvoice><cntemail>mde.analytics@state.mn.us</cntemail></cntinfo></distrib></distinfo><metainfo><metd>20251031</metd><metstdn>Minnesota Geographic Metadata Guidelines</metstdn><metstdv>1.2</metstdv><metextns><onlink>http://www.gis.state.mn.us/stds/metadata.htm</onlink></metextns><langmeta Sync="TRUE">en</langmeta><mettc Sync="TRUE">local time</mettc><metextns><onlink Sync="TRUE">http://www.esri.com/metadata/esriprof80.html</onlink><metprof Sync="TRUE">ESRI Metadata Profile</metprof></metextns><metc><cntinfo><cntperp><cntorg>Minnesota Department of Education</cntorg><cntper>Data Specialists</cntper></cntperp><cntpos>Analytics Team</cntpos><cntaddr><addrtype>mailing and physical</addrtype><address>400 NE Stinson Blvd</address><city>Minneapolis</city><state>MN</state><postal>55413</postal></cntaddr><cntvoice>651-582-8200</cntvoice><cntemail>mde.analytics@state.mn.us</cntemail></cntinfo></metc></metainfo><Esri><ModDate>20110505</ModDate><ModTime>18304300</ModTime><CreaDate>20080904</CreaDate><CreaTime>15035800</CreaTime><SyncOnce>FALSE</SyncOnce><SyncDate>20061229</SyncDate><SyncTime>10193300</SyncTime><MetaID>{DE5A3018-42D5-4D6F-A334-ED86D96CDFDC}</MetaID></Esri><mdDateSt Sync="TRUE">20110505</mdDateSt><dataIdInfo><envirDesc Sync="TRUE">Microsoft Windows XP Version 5.1 (Build 2600) Service Pack 2; ESRI ArcCatalog 9.1.0.780</envirDesc><dataLang><languageCode Sync="TRUE" value="en"></languageCode></dataLang><idCitation><resTitle Sync="TRUE">nonpub07</resTitle><presForm><PresFormCd Sync="TRUE" value="005"></PresFormCd></presForm></idCitation><spatRpType><SpatRepTypCd Sync="TRUE" value="001"></SpatRepTypCd></spatRpType><dataExt><geoEle><GeoBndBox esriExtentType="native"><westBL Sync="TRUE">199551.594331</westBL><eastBL Sync="TRUE">636157.436282</eastBL><northBL Sync="TRUE">5385889.998627</northBL><southBL Sync="TRUE">4820393.00165</southBL><exTypeCode Sync="TRUE">1</exTypeCode></GeoBndBox></geoEle></dataExt><geoBox esriExtentType="decdegrees"><westBL Sync="TRUE">-97.071908</westBL><eastBL Sync="TRUE">-91.152757</eastBL><northBL Sync="TRUE">48.626078</northBL><southBL Sync="TRUE">43.476096</southBL><exTypeCode Sync="TRUE">1</exTypeCode></geoBox></dataIdInfo><mdLang><languageCode Sync="TRUE" value="en"></languageCode></mdLang><mdStanName Sync="TRUE">ISO 19115 Geographic Information - Metadata</mdStanName><mdStanVer Sync="TRUE">DIS_ESRI1.0</mdStanVer><mdChar><CharSetCd Sync="TRUE" value="004"></CharSetCd></mdChar><mdHrLv><ScopeCd Sync="TRUE" value="005"></ScopeCd></mdHrLv><mdHrLvName Sync="TRUE">dataset</mdHrLvName><distInfo><distributor><distorTran><onLineSrc><orDesc Sync="TRUE">002</orDesc><linkage Sync="TRUE">file://\\ITDBX6K391\C$\MDEFNS_Data\Spatial_Data\SD_Data\SY2008-09\Final Metadata\pubsch08</linkage><protocol Sync="TRUE">Local Area Network</protocol></onLineSrc><transSize Sync="TRUE">0.016</transSize></distorTran><distorFormat><formatName Sync="TRUE">Shapefile</formatName></distorFormat></distributor></distInfo><spatRepInfo><VectSpatRep><topLvl><TopoLevCd Sync="TRUE" value="001"></TopoLevCd></topLvl><geometObjs Name="nonpub07"><geoObjTyp><GeoObjTypCd Sync="TRUE" value="004"></GeoObjTypCd></geoObjTyp><geoObjCnt Sync="TRUE">602</geoObjCnt></geometObjs></VectSpatRep></spatRepInfo><refSysInfo><RefSystem><refSysID><identCode Sync="TRUE">NAD_1983_UTM_Zone_15N</identCode></refSysID></RefSystem></refSysInfo><eainfo><overview><eaover>Basic identifying attributes provided with each record. Sample record below for guidance.

osm_id:	1390550707
name:	Cass Lake-Bena Elementary
address:	15271 61st Ave NW
city:	Cass Lake
state:	MN
zip:	56633


Please note that the OpenStreetMap (OSM) ID is provided as informational only; OSM does not preserve permanent IDs and so this ID may not exist in future datasets. Please also note that the address information shown is from MDE ORG's physical address designation; while these addresses are occasionally the same as a mailing address, the addresses in this dataset should NOT be used for sending mail.</eaover></overview></eainfo></metadata>