<metadata><idinfo><citation><citeinfo><title>Park and Pool Lots</title><origin>Metropolitan Council</origin><pubinfo><publish>Metropolitan Council - Metro Transit</publish></pubinfo><pubdate>periodically revised</pubdate><onlink>https://gisdata.mn.gov/dataset/us-mn-state-metc-trans-park-and-pool-lots</onlink></citeinfo></citation><descript><abstract>The Park and Pool Lots layer contains an inventory of park and pool lots throughout the Twin Cities Metropolitan area and surrounding counties, including communities in the neighboring state of Wisconsin. These locations allow commuters the ability to park their private vehicles for extended periods of time and meet others for commuter pooling purposes. 

The dataset was geocoded using TLG centerline streets. When specific site details were available, the geography was moved off street lines to actual facility locations using orthophotographic imagery as a base layer. All attempts were made to correctly reflect the real lot locations; however the positional accuracy of this data cannot be guaranteed.

This inventory is maintained as a geographic record of the parking lots locations, and can be utilized alongside the "Park-and-Ride Annual Survey" table for historic capacity and utilization figures of park and pool locations. </abstract><purpose>To identify park and pool locations in the Twin Cities metropolitan area and surrounding counties, including communities in the neighboring state of Wisconsin. </purpose><supplinf>Twin Cities Metropolitan Area - including Minnesota Counties: Anoka, Carver, Chisago, Dakota, Goodhue, Hennepin, Isanti, Le Sueur, Mille Lacs, Ramsey, Rice, Scott, Sherburne, Stearns, Washington, Wright; Wisconsin Counties: Dunn, St. Croix</supplinf></descript><timeperd><timeinfo><sngdate><caldate>20200210</caldate></sngdate></timeinfo><current>Park and pool locations are accurate as of the Time Period of Content date. </current></timeperd><status><progress>Complete</progress><update>As needed</update></status><spdom><bounding><westbc>-94.581</westbc><eastbc>-91.719</eastbc><northbc>45.628</northbc><southbc>44.385</southbc></bounding></spdom><keywords><place><placekey>Twin Cities, Minnesota, Anoka County, Carver County, Chisago County, Dakota County, Goodhue County, Hennepin County, Isanti County, Le Sueur County, Mille Lacs County, Ramsey County, Rice County, Scott County, Sherburne County, Stearns County, Washington County, Wright County, Dunn County, St. Croix County</placekey></place><theme><themekey>Transit Centers, Transit Stops, Transit Routes, Transit Patterns by Node Segments, transit, buses, nodes, stops, transportation</themekey><themekt>None</themekt></theme></keywords><accconst>None. This dataset is public domain under the Minnesota Government Data Practices Act (Minnesota Statutes Chapter 13). If the dataset is not available from the Online Linkage in Section 6, please contact the Distribution Contact Person.</accconst><useconst>None. This dataset is public domain under the Minnesota Government Data Practices Act (Minnesota Statutes Chapter 13).</useconst><crossref><citeinfo><title>Park &amp; Rides and Transit Centers</title></citeinfo></crossref><native>ArcGIS 9x</native><ptcontac><cntinfo><cntperp><cntorg>Metropolitan Council - Metro Transit</cntorg><cntper>Jenny Ackerson</cntper></cntperp><cntpos>Planner - NR</cntpos><cntaddr><addrtype>mailing and physical</addrtype><address>560 6th Ave N</address><city>St. Paul</city><state>MN</state><postal>55106</postal></cntaddr><cntvoice>612.349.7366</cntvoice><cntemail>jenny.ackerson@metrotransit.org</cntemail></cntinfo></ptcontac></idinfo><dataqual><attracc><attraccr>Attributes are considered accurate. See the Entity and Attribute Overview for more details.</attraccr></attracc><logic>The dataset is topologically 'clean'.</logic><posacc><horizpa><horizpar>Orthophotos were used in referencing park and pool locations. Positional accuracy varies throughout the dataset. </horizpar></horizpa></posacc><complete>All park and pools historically tracked for Metro Transit Annual Park and Ride Survey purposes are included in the dataset.</complete></dataqual><spdoinfo><indspref>None</indspref><direct>Point</direct><mgmg3obj>Point</mgmg3obj><mgmg3til>One file for entire metro area.</mgmg3til></spdoinfo><eainfo><overview><eaover>Park and Pool Lots Attributes

TCode: Unique value used by Metro Transit for identification of facilities

PnRNum: Identification number for park and pool used in the Annual Survey Table

Name: Name of the park and pool lot

Status: Current status of the facility
Open = Facility is open for use
Closed = Facility is permantly closed

Address: Parking lot address

City: City in which parking lot is located

Provider: State DOT that maintains park and pool lot

LocDetails: Lot location details (intersection, quadrant, portion of parking lot, etc.)

YearOpen: The year in which this lot opened for service

YearClose: The year in which this lot has closed down, if applicable

CurrentCpct: Number of parking spaces currently available at this lot

SharedUse: Indicates whether the lot is shared with another use
Y = Yes, lot is shared with another use
N = No, lot is standalone and not shared with another use

ShrUseDesc: Description of the shared or complementary use of the parking lot, if applicable

Notes: Any additional notes regarding this parking lot</eaover></overview></eainfo><distinfo><resdesc>ParkAndPoolLots</resdesc><distliab>NOTICE:  The Geographic Information System (GIS) Data to which this notice is attached are made available pursuant to the Minnesota Government Data Practices Act (Minnesota Statutes Chapter 13).  THE GIS DATA ARE PROVIDED TO YOU AS IS AND WITHOUT ANY WARRANTY AS TO THEIR PERFORMANCE, MERCHANTABILITY, OR FITNESS FOR ANY PARTICULAR PURPOSE.  The GIS Data were developed by the Metropolitan Council for its own internal business purposes.  The Metropolitan Council does not represent or warrant that the GIS Data or the data documentation are error-free, complete, current, or accurate.  You are responsible for any consequences resulting from your use of the GIS Data or your reliance on the GIS Data.  You should consult the data documentation for this particular GIS Data to determine the limitations of the GIS Data and the precision with which the GIS Data may depict distance, direction, location, or other geographic features.  If you transmit or provide the GIS Data (or any portion of it) to another user, it is recommended that the GIS Data include a copy of this disclaimer and this metadata.</distliab><stdorder><digform><digtinfo><formname>ArcView Shape File</formname><formvern>ArcGIS 9x</formvern><transize>0.1 Meg. for zip file.</transize></digtinfo></digform><ordering>See Online Linkage Below</ordering></stdorder><distrib><cntinfo><cntperp><cntorg>Metropolitan Council - Metro Transit</cntorg><cntper>Jenny Ackerson</cntper></cntperp><cntpos>Planner - NR</cntpos><cntaddr><addrtype>mailing and physical</addrtype><address>560 6th Ave N</address><city>St. Paul</city><state>MN</state><postal>55106</postal></cntaddr><cntvoice>612.349.7366</cntvoice><cntemail>jenny.ackerson@metrotransit.org</cntemail></cntinfo></distrib></distinfo><metainfo><metd>20230511</metd><metstdn>Minnesota Geographic Metadata Guidelines</metstdn><metstdv>1.2</metstdv><metextns><onlink>http://www.mngeo.state.mn.us/committee/standards/mgmg/metadata.htm</onlink></metextns><metc><cntinfo><cntperp><cntorg>Metropolitan Council - Metro Transit</cntorg><cntper>Jenny Ackerson</cntper></cntperp><cntpos>Planner - NR</cntpos><cntaddr><addrtype>mailing and physical</addrtype><address>560 6th Ave N</address><city>St. Paul</city><state>MN</state><postal>55106</postal></cntaddr><cntvoice>612.349.7366</cntvoice><cntemail>jenny.ackerson@metrotransit.org</cntemail></cntinfo></metc></metainfo><Esri><ModDate>20110721</ModDate><ModTime>14581600</ModTime></Esri><mdDateSt Sync="TRUE">20110721</mdDateSt><spref><horizsys><planar><gridsys><gridsysn>Universal Transverse Mercator</gridsysn><utm><utmzone>15</utmzone></utm></gridsys><planci><plandu>meters</plandu></planci></planar><geodetic><horizdn>NAD83</horizdn><ellips>GRS80</ellips></geodetic></horizsys></spref></metadata>